Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
= 权力的游戏 第1季第5集 =
狼狮之争
首播时间: 2011年5月15日
== 翻译: freesand ==
(君临城)
(鹰巢城)
(临冬城)
(绝境长城)
( Theme music playing )
= Game of Thrones 1x05 =
The Wolf and the Lion Original Air Date on May 15, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
(维斯多斯拉克)
原著: 乔治马丁
( Horse whinnies )
( Men shouting )
修夫爵士在都城有亲人吗?
Ned: Does Ser Hugh have any family in the capital?
没有.
No.
昨晚是我替他守的灵.
I stood vigil for him myself last night.
他在这里无依无靠.
He had no one else.
在此之前他从未穿过这套盔甲.
He'd never worn this armor before.
他运气太坏--
Bad luck for him--
对上了魔山.
going against the Mountain.
谁定的比武次序?
Who determines the draw?
所有骑士抽签决定, 史塔克大人.
All the knights draw straws, Lord Stark.
是的.
Aye.
但是谁主持抽签?
But who holds the straws?
有劳你们了, 嬷嬷.
You've done good work, sisters.
人生真是变幻无常. 曾几何时
Life is strange. Not so many years ago
我们还在三叉戟河畔彼此对垒.
we fought as enemies at the trident.
幸好我们没在战场上碰面, 巴利斯坦爵士.
I'm glad we never met on the field, Ser Barristan.
我妻子也该感到庆幸.
As is my wife.
她年纪轻轻的不应成为寡妇.
I don't think the widow's life would suit her.
你太谦虚了.
( Chuckles ) You're too modest.
我亲眼看见你打倒了许多勇武的骑士.
I've seen you cut down a dozen great knights.
我父亲曾经告诉我
My father once told me
你是他见过的人中武艺最强的.
you were the best he'd ever seen.
他在武学方面从来不会看走眼.
I never knew the man to be wrong about matters of combat.
你父亲是一个好人.
He was a fine man, your father.
疯王对他犯下了可怕的罪过.
What the Mad King did to him was a terrible crime.
那个小伙子--
And that lad--
他几个月前还是侍从.
he was a squire until a few months ago.
他怎么置办得起这样一套新盔甲?
How could he afford a new suit of armor?
也许艾林大人给了他一些钱?
Perhaps Lord Arryn left him some money?
我听说国王今天打算参加比武.
I hear the King wants to joust today.
是的, 但这绝对不行.
Yes, that will never happen.
劳勃总是想做就做.
( Chuckles ) Robert tends to do what he wants.
如果每回都照国王的意思办,
If the King got what he wanted all the time,
恐怕现在还是天下大乱.
he'd still be fighting a damned rebellion.
这铠甲太小, 陛下. 穿不上的.
It's made too small, Your Grace. It won't go.
你是个愚蠢的婊子养的.
Your mother was a dumb whore
你听到没有?
with a fat ass. Did you know that?
瞧瞧这个笨蛋! 没有卵蛋, 没有脑子.
Look at this idiot! One ball and no brains.
连帮人穿铠甲都不会.
He can't even put a man's armor on him properly.
你太胖了, 所以穿不下.
You're too fat for your armor.
太胖? 太胖, 是吗?
Fat? Fat, is it?
你就这样对国王讲话吗?
Is that how you speak to your King?
( Laughing )
很好笑, 是吗?
That was funny, is it?
不, 陛下.
No, Your Grace.
不? 你不喜欢首相说的笑话?
No? You don't like the Hand's joke?
你让这可怜孩子无所适从了.
You're torturing the poor boy.
首相说了. 国王太胖了所以穿不下.
You heard the Hand. The King's too fat for his armor.
去找个胸甲撑子-- 快去!
Go find the breastplate stretcher-- now!
"胸甲撑子"?
- ( Laughter ) - "The breastplate stretcher"?
让他上哪儿去找?
How long before he figures it out?
你杜撰出来的东西吧.
Maybe you should have one invented.
好了, 好了.
All right, all right.
你等着看吧-- 我还记得怎么使长枪.
But you watch me out there-- I still know how to point a Lance.
你不该参加比武. 让年轻人上吧.
You have no business jousting. Leave that for the young men.
为什么, 因为我是国王? 得了. 我只想打打人罢了!
Why, because I'm king? Piss on that. I want to hit somebody!
- 那谁敢对你还手呢? - 谁都行啊.
- And who's going to hit you back? - Anybody who can.
- 反正最后还骑在马鞍上的-- - 一定会是你.
- And the last man in his saddle-- - Will be you.
七国上下绝不会有人
There's not a man in the Seven Kingdoms
敢冒险伤到你.
would risk hurting you.
你的意思是那些胆小鬼会故意让我赢?
Are you telling me those cowards would let me win?
是的.
Aye.
- 喝吧. - 我不渴.
- Drink. - I'm not thirsty.
快喝. 这是国王的命令.
Drink. Your King commands it.
诸神在上,
Gods,
我竟然胖得穿不下铠甲.
too fat for my armor.
你的侍从... 是兰尼斯特家的孩子?
Your squire... A Lannister boy?
嗯. 一个大白痴,
Mm. A bloody idiot,
瑟曦坚持要我收他.
but Cersei insisted.
都要感谢琼恩艾林让我娶她.
I have Jon Arryn to thank for her.
"瑟曦兰尼斯特是个好对象," 他告诉我.
"Cersei Lannister will make a good match," he told me.
"你需要她父亲的支持."
"You'll need her father on your side."
我本以为当国王可以做自己想做的事.
I thought being King meant I could do whatever I wanted.
够了. 我们去看他们比武吧.
Enough of this. Let's go watch 'em ride.
至少我还可以闻闻血腥味.
At least I can smell someone else's blood.
- 劳勃? - 什么?
- Robert? - What?
哦.
Oh. ( Laughs )
十分引人注目, 嗯?
An inspiring sight for the people, eh?
快, 拜见国王! 快鞠躬, 一群废物!
Come, bow before your King! Bow, you shits!
( Polite laughter )
( Cheering )
- 艾莉亚在哪儿? - 她去上舞蹈课了.
- Where's Arya? - At her dancing lessons.
百花骑士.
The knight of the flowers.
谢谢你, 洛拉斯爵士.
Thank you, Ser Loras.
( Neighs )
( Horse fussing )
别让格雷果爵士伤害他.
Don't let Ser Gregor hurt him.
- 嘿. - 我不敢看.
- Hey. - I can't watch.
一百金龙赌魔山赢.
100 gold dragons on the Mountain.
我和你赌.
I'll take that bet.
现在我该拿那一百金龙买点什么呢?
Now what will I buy with 100 gold dragons?
来自多恩的美酒?
A dozen barrels of Dornish wine?
来自里斯的姑娘?
Or a girl from the pleasure houses of Lys?
你也可以买一个朋友.
Or you could even buy a friend.
他会死的.
He's going to die.
洛拉斯爵士武艺很好.
Ser Loras rides well.
( Neighing )
( Fanfare )
- ( Gasps ) - ( Laughs )
真可惜, 小指头.
Such a shame, Littlefinger.
你本可以拥有一个朋友.
It would have been so nice for you to have a friend.
告诉我, 蓝礼大人,
And tell me, Lord Renly,
你打算何时去拥有你的朋友?
when will you be having your friend?
( Neighs )
洛拉斯知道他那母马正在发情.
Loras knew his mare was in heat.
确实很狡猾.
Quite crafty, really.
洛拉斯绝不是故意的.
Ser Loras would never do that.
耍花招毫无荣誉可言.
There's no honor in tricks.
没有荣誉, 但足以赢得大笔金钱.
No honor and quite a bit of gold.
拿剑来!
- ( Helmet clanks ) - Sword!
( Horse neighs )
- ( Gasps ) - ( Neighs )
- ( Gasps ) - ( Grunts )
不要碰他!
Leave him be!
( Growls )
立刻住手, 这是国王的命令!
Stop this madness in the name of your King!
让他去吧!
Robert: Let him go!
我欠您一条命, 爵士.
I owe you my life, Ser.
我不是什么爵士.
I'm no Ser.
( Cheering )
拿下他的头罩.
Remove his hood.
晚间, 被俘的小恶魔
Marillion: ? on that Eve, the captive Imp ?
滚鞍下马步履蹒跚
? downwards from his horse did limp ?
自负傲气消失不见
? no more would he preen and primp ?
金缕红袍沾满灰尘
? in garb of red and gold. ?
这不是国王大道.
Tyrion: This isn't the Kingsroad.
你说我们是去临冬城.
You said we were riding for Winterfell.
我是说了... 很多次而且很大声.
I did... Often and loudly.
确实高明.
Very wise.
他们会骑马追赶,
They'll be out in droves,
朝错误的方向去找我.
looking for me in the wrong place.
现在消息可能已传到我父亲那里.
Word's probably gotten to my father by now.
他会为此开出一大笔赏金.
He'll be offering a handsome reward.
人人都知道: 兰尼斯特有债必还.
Everyone knows a Lannister always pays his debts.
你能给我松绑吗?
Would you be so good as to untie me?
- 我为什么要这样做? - 为什么不?
- And why would I do that? - Why not?
我还会逃跑吗?
Am I going to run?
山地部落会为抢我的鞋子杀掉我.
The hill tribes would kill me for my boots.
或者我会先被影子山猫吃掉.
Unless a Shadowcat ate me first.
你完全不用担心影子山猫和山地部落.
Shadowcats and hill tribes are the least of your concerns.
啊, 朝东的路.
Ah, the eastern road.
我们是去艾林谷.
We're going to the Vale.
你带我去你妹妹那里
You're taking me to your sister's
为你想像中我的罪行负责.
to answer for my imagined crimes.
告诉我, 史塔克夫人, 你上次见到你妹妹是在什么时候?
Tell me, Lady Stark, when was the last time you saw your sister?
五年前.
Five years ago.
她已经变了很多.
She's changed.
他过去有点感情用事, 但现在--
She was always a bit touched, but now--
你不如在这儿把我杀了.
you might as well kill me here.
- 我可不会暗下杀手, 兰尼斯特. - 我也不会!
- I am not a murderer, Lannister. - Neither am I!
谋害贵公子的事与我毫无瓜葛.
I had nothing to do with the attempt on your son's life.
- 那把匕首-- - 怎样的笨蛋
- The dagger found-- - What sort of imbecile
才会把自己的武器交给刺客用?
arms an assassin with his own blade?
- 我把他嘴巴塞上吧? - 为什么?
- Should I gag him? - Why?
因为我说得太有道理?
Am I starting to make sense?
罗德利克!
- ( Thuds, grunts ) - Catelyn: Rodrik!
( Screaming )
夫人, 这边走.
My Lady, this way.
给我松绑.
Untie me.
我要是死了, 你怎么查清真相?
If I die, what's the point?
( Neighs )
啊!
Ah!
( Screams )
( Heavy breathing )
罗德利克?
Rodrik?
我没事, 夫人.
I'll be fine, My Lady.
别让自己身上沾满血.
There's no need to bloody yourself.
你第一次杀人?
Your first?
你需要找个女人.
You need a woman.
打斗之后找个女人最来劲.
Nothing like a woman after a fight.
她肯得话我也愿意.
I'm willing if she is.
( Laughing )
布兰.
Bran.
铁群岛.
Bran: The Iron Islands.
纹章: 一只海怪.
Sigil: A Kraken.
箴言: 强取胜于苦耕.
Words: We do not sow.
- 领主? - 葛雷乔伊.
- Lords? - The Greyjoys.
特长: 高超的箭术,
Famed for their skills at archery,
航海技术和床上技巧.
navigation and lovemaking.
( Laughs )
还有失败的叛乱.
And failed rebellions.
纹章: 一只雄鹿--
Sigil: A stag--
戴宝冠的雄鹿, 由于劳勃称王.
a crowned stag now that Robert's King.
- 很好. - 箴言: 怒火燎原.
- Good. - Words: Ours is the fury.
- 领主: 拜拉席恩. - 嗯嗯.
- Lords: The Baratheons. - Mm-hmm.
西境.
The Westerlands.
- 纹章: 一只雄狮. - 嗯.
- Sigil: A lion. - Mmm.
箴言: 兰尼斯特有债必还.
Words: A Lannister always pays his debts.
不对.
No.
这句话是很有名, 但不是他们家族箴言.
A common saying, but not their official motto.
领主: 兰尼斯特.
- ( Arrow thunks ) - Lords: The Lannisters.
- 我问他们的箴言. - 我不知道.
- We're still on their words. - I don't know them.
你知道的. 想想看.
You do know them. Think.
"不屈不挠."
"Unbowed, unbent, unbroken."
- 那是马泰尔家族的. - "为正义而怒."
- That's House Martell. - "Righteous in wrath."
- 那是豪伍德家族的. - "家族, 责任, 荣誉."
- House Hornwood. - "Family, duty, honor."
那是徒利家族-- 你母亲家的.
Those are Tully words-- your mother's.
- 我们还玩游戏吗? - 家族, 责任, 荣誉...
- Are we playing a game? - Family, duty, honor...
- 这顺序对吗? - 当然对.
- Is that the right order? - You know it is.
家族在第一位?
Family comes first?
你母亲离开临冬城
Your mother had to leave Winterfell
是为了保护家族.
to protect the family.
她怎么保护家族
How can she protect the family
如果她人都不在家?
if she's not with her family?
你母亲在你床边
Your mother sat by your bed
守了三个月等你醒来--
for three weeks while you slept--
然后她就走了!
and then she left!
你出生的时候,
When you were born, I was the one
是我为你的母亲接生.
who pulled you from your mother.
是我将你放到他手上.
I placed you in her arms.
从那一刻起直到她去世的那一刻,
From that moment until the moment she dies,
她都会一直爱着你.
she will love you.
全心全意.
Absolutely.
- 不顾一切. - 那她为什么走?
- Fiercely. - Why did she leave?
我还不能告诉你,
( Sighs ) I still can't tell you,
- 但她很快就会回家. - 你知道她在哪儿?
- but she will be home soon. - Do you know where she is now?
现在?
- ( Arrow thunks ) - Today?
不, 我不知道.
No, I don't.
那你怎么能保证她很快就会回家?
Then how can you promise me she'll be home soon?
我担心你太聪明了, 有时这并不一定好.
Sometimes I worry you're too smart for your own good.
我再也不能射箭了.
I'll never shoot another arrow.
谁说的?
And where is that written?
- 射箭要用上腿部的力量. - 嗯.
- You need legs to work a bow. - Hmm.
如果提利昂大人设计的马鞍有效得话,
If the saddle Lord Tyrion designed actually works,
你可以学习在马背上射箭.
you could learn to shoot a bow from horseback.
真的
Really
多斯拉克小孩四岁就开始骑马射箭.
Dothraki boys learn when they're four years old.
难道你不可以吗?
Why shouldn't you?
( Grunting )
( Moans )
嘘, 小声点.
Shh, keep it down.
你本不能到城堡里来.
You're not supposed to be inside the castle walls.
我本以为你在这儿很有地位.
I thought you were supposed to be an important person around here.
对你这样人的来说足够有地位了.
Important enough for the likes of you.
你可不是我见识过的唯一一个贵族.
You're not the only nobleman in my life, you know.
还有谁, 小恶魔?
Who, the Imp?
我看他只是半个贵族.
I'd call him half a nobleman.
嫉妒了?
Jealous?
我为什么要嫉妒?
Why should I be jealous?
任何口袋里有几个铜板的人都可以拥有你一晚.
Anyone with a few coppers in his pocket can own you for the night.
侏儒那玩意有多大?
What's a dwarf like down below?
我一直很好奇.
I've always wondered.
- 你会吃惊的. - 嗯?
- Might surprise you. - Hmm?
他手指上的技巧也很好.
He's good with his fingers too.
还有他的舌头.
And his tongue.
给小费也很慷慨.
Generous tipper.
兰尼斯特家挥金如土.
I guess gold is cheap for a Lannister.
你嫉妒了.
You are jealous.
我来自葛雷乔伊家族.
I'm a Greyjoy.
我们统治铁群岛三百年之久.
We've been lords of the Iron Islands for 300 years.
维斯特洛没有哪个家族敢看不起我们,
There's not a family in Westeros that can look down on us,
兰尼斯特家也不敢.
not even the Lannisters.
那史塔克家呢?
And what about the Starks?
我八岁起就是史塔克大人的养子.
I've been Lord Stark's ward since I was eight years old.
养子-- 听起来倒不错.
A ward-- that's a nice word for it.
你父亲曾反叛劳勃国王
Your father rebelled against King Robert
- 如果他再反一次-- - 我父亲是
- and if he does it again-- - My father fought
为了族人的自由而战.
for the freedom of his people.
你父亲做了些什么? 干了一个厨娘, 生了一个婊子.
What did your father do? Fucked a cook and whelped a whore.
你真是个开不得玩笑的孩子.
You're a very serious boy.
- 我可不是孩子. - 哦, 你是.
- I'm not a boy. - Oh yes, you are.
连你的命根子都是开不得玩笑的.
A serious boy with a serious cock.
我不打算付你钱了.
I don't want to pay for it.
那你还是去找个老婆吧.
Then get yourself a wife.
来吧.
- Arya: Come on. - ( Meows )
我不会伤害你的.
- I'm not gonna hurt you. - ( Meows )
( Meows )
你的儿子怎么样了, 大人?
How is your son, My Lord?
他再也不能走路了.
He'll never walk again.
他的神志清醒了?
But his mind is sound?
是这样.
So they say.
那还算幸运.
A blessing then.
我也是在很小时身体就残缺了.
I suffered an early mutilation myself.
有些门对我来说永远关闭...
Some doors close forever...
另外一些却意外地向我开启.
Others open in the most unexpected places.
我可以坐下吗?
May I?
如果我将要告诉你的事被别人听到,
If the wrong ears heard what I'm about to tell you,
我可能会掉脑袋.
off comes my head.
那时谁会为可怜的瓦里斯哀悼呢?
And who would mourn poor Varys then?
天南地北, 没有人会为蜘蛛而歌唱啊.
North or South, they sing no songs for spiders.
但有些事必须让你知道.
But there are things you must know.
你是国王之手, 而国王是个蠢才--
You are the King's Hand and the King is a fool--
我知道他是你的朋友, 但他确实是个蠢才--
your friend, I know, but a fool--
注定要完蛋, 除非你能救他.
and doomed unless you save him.
我到都城已经一个月了.
I've been in the capital a month.
为什么你等到现在才告诉我这些?
Why have you waited so long to tell me this?
因为我不信任你.
I didn't trust you.
那现在你为什么又信任我?
So why do you trust me now?
并非只有王后一个人
The Queen is not the only one
在密切注视你的行动.
who has been watching you closely.
在都城里注重荣誉的人屈指可数.
There are few men of honor in the capital.
你是其中之一.
You are one of them.
我认为我也是其中之一,
I would like to believe I am another,
虽然也许令人难以置信.
strange as that may seem.
国王面临怎样的危险?
What sort of doom does the King face?
和琼恩艾林一样.
The same sort as Jon Arryn.
那东西叫里斯之泪.
The tears of Lys, they call it.
非常罕见而昂贵,
A rare and costly thing,
味道清甜如水.
as clear and tasteless as water.
不留一点痕迹.
It leaves no trace.
是谁下的毒?
Who gave it to him?
无疑是某个与他非常亲近的人. 但是哪一个呢?
Some dear friend, no doubt. But which one?
可疑的对象太多了.
There were many.
艾林大人是个和蔼可亲的人.
Lord Arryn was a kind and trusting man.
确有这么个孩子.
( Sighs ) There was one boy.
他的一切都是琼恩艾林给的.
All he was he owed to Jon Arryn.
那个侍从, 修夫爵士?
The squire, Ser Hugh?
可惜他死不逢时,
Pity what happened to him,
本来他的前途一片光明.
just when his life seemed to be going so nicely.
如果是修夫爵士下的毒--
If Ser Hugh poisoned him--
那是谁指使修夫爵士的?
who paid Ser Hugh?
某个出得起价钱的人.
Someone who could afford it.
琼恩一向与人为善.
Jon was a man of peace.
他当了十七年的首相--
He was Hand for 17 years--
十七年的太平时光.
17 good years.
为什么要杀他?
Why kill him?
他问太多问题了.
He started asking questions.
( Meows )
他已经找到了一个私生子.
Man's voice: He's found one bastard already.
他还拿到了那本书.
He has the book.
他迟早会查出真相.
- The rest will come. - ( Lock clicks )
等他查出真相, 他会怎么做?
Man #2: And when he knows the truth, what will he do?
只有诸神知道.
The gods alone know.
那群蠢蛋想杀他儿子.
The fools tried to kill his son.
更糟糕的是-- 他们搞砸了.
What's worse-- they botched it.
狼和狮很快就会打成一团.
The wolf and the lion will be at each other's throats.
- 我们很快就要开战了, 朋友. - 现在开战有什么用?
- We will be at war soon, my friend. - What good is war now?
我们还没准备好.
We're not ready.
既然死了一个首相, 为什么不能死第二个?
If one Hand can die, why not a second?
这个首相和那个不同.
This Hand is not the other.
我们需要时间.
We need time.
卓戈卡奥是不会在他儿子诞生前就行动的.
Khal Drogo will not make his move until his son is born.
你知道这些野蛮人的德行.
You know how these savages are.
你要我 "拖一下". 我可要你 "快一点".
"Delay," you say. "Move fast," I reply.
这不再是一场两人游戏了.
This is no longer a game for two players.
从来都不是.
It never was.
最先到场, 最后离开.
The first to arrive and the last to leave.
我赞赏你的勤奋.
I admire your industry.
你真是悄无声息.
You do move quietly.
我们都有自己的特长.
We all have our qualities.
今天你看起来有点孤单.
You look a bit lonely today.
今晚你应该到我的妓院来逛逛.
You should pay a visit to my brothel this evening.
认识下当家小生.
First boy is on the house.
我想你是弄错了.
I think you're mistaking business with pleasure.
是吗?
Am I?
那些在你耳旁低语的小小鸟儿--
All those birds that whisper in your ear--
漂亮的小东西.
such pretty little things.
相信我,
Trust me,
任何取向我们都能满足.
we accommodate all inclinations.
哦, 我相信.
Oh, I'm sure.
我听说雷德温大人喜欢很小的男孩.
Lord Redwyne likes his boys very young, I hear.
我重视美貌和见识--
I'm a purveyor of beauty and discretion--
两者同样重要.
both equally important.
我想美貌是一种主观感受, 不是吗?
Though I suppose beauty is a subjective quality, no?
是不是真的
Is it true that
腾石的马隆爵士喜欢断肢者?
Ser Marlon of Tumblestone prefers amputees?
人的喜好千奇百怪.
All desires are valid to a man with a full purse.
我听说过最可怕的传言是有关一位领主
And I heard the most awful rumor about a certain lord
喜欢新鲜的死尸.
with a taste for fresh cadavers.
要满足这种喜好恐怕是相当困难.
Must be enormously difficult to accommodate that inclination.
得有人专门--
The logistics alone--
去找漂亮的尚未腐烂的尸体.
to find beautiful corpses before they rot.
严格地说, 做这种事
Strictly speaking, such a thing
违反国王的律法.
would not be in accordance with the King's laws.
严格地说.
Strictly speaking.
告诉我-- 是否有人在某处
Tell me-- does someone somewhere
将你的卵蛋保存在一个小盒子里?
keep your balls in a little box?
我常常感到好奇.
I've often wondered.
你是否知道我不知道它们在哪里?
Do you know I have no idea where they are?
我们曾经如此亲密
- And we had been so close. - ( Chuckles )
不用再说我了. 再说说看
But enough about me. How have you been
我们上次见面之后日子里你过得如何?
since we last saw each other?
是你上次看到我之后还是我上次看到你之后?
Since you last saw me or since I last saw you?
我上次看到你,
Now the last time  I saw you,
你正在和国王之手谈话.
you were talking to the Hand of the King.
- 你亲眼看到我? - 我亲眼看到.
- Saw me with your own eyes? - Eyes I own.
是为国事.
Council business.
我们都有很多事要和奈德史塔克谈.
We all have so much to discuss with Ned Stark.
大家知道你一直都喜欢
Everyone's well aware of your enduring fondness
史塔克大人的妻子.
for Lord Stark's wife.
如果兰尼斯特家是谋杀史塔克家孩子的幕后主使
If the Lannisters were behind the attempt on the Stark boy's life
而且如果有人说是你帮助
and it was discovered that you helped
史塔克家得出这个结论...
the Starks come to that conclusion...
如果王后听到了风声--
To think a simple word to the Queen--
- 想想就令人发抖. - 哦.
- one shudders at the thought. - Ooh.
你知道吗? 我想我上次看到你
But you know something? I do believe that I have seen you
是在你上次看到我之后.
even more recently than you have seen me.
- 是吗? - 是的.
- Have you? - Yes.
今天稍早的时候, 我记得很清楚
Earlier today, I distinctly recall
看到你在史塔克大人的房间里和他谈话.
seeing you talking to Lord Stark in his chambers.
当时你在床底下?
Was that you under the bed?
而在那之后不久
And not long after that
我又看到你陪同一位
when I saw you escorting a certain
远道而来的贵客...
foreign dignitary...
为了国事?
Council business?
当然你可以有住在峡海对岸的朋友.
Of course you would have friends from across the Narrow Sea.
毕竟你本人就是从那边过来的.
You're from there yourself, after all.
我们是朋友, 对吧, 瓦里斯大人?
We're friends, aren't we, Lord Varys?
但愿我们是.
I'd like to think we are.
那么你可以想象我所承受的压力,
So you can imagine my burden,
恐怕国王会因我对朋友的同情而怀疑我.
wondering if the King might question my friend's sympathies.
身处两难境地, 向左是忠于朋友,
To stand at a crossroads where turning left means loyalty to a friend,
向右是忠于国家--
turning right loyalty to the realm--
- 哦, 拜托你. - 我自己的处境
- Oh, please. - To find myself in a position
只要国王听说一个字--
- where a simple word to the King-- - ( Door opens )
你们两个在策划什么阴谋?
What are you two conspiring about?
嗯, 不管是什么, 最好快一点.
Well, whatever it is, you'd best hurry up.
我兄弟要来了.
My brother is coming.
参加御前会议?
To a small council meeting?
来自远方令人不安的消息.
Disturbing news from far away.
你听说了吗?
Haven't you heard?
( Birds cawing, waves breaking )
你快滚开. 这里不准乞讨.
Off with you. No begging.
我不是乞丐. 我住这里.
I'm not a beggar. I live here.
你是要我赏你两个耳刮子才听得懂?
D'you want a smack on your ear to help you with your hearing?
我要找我父亲.
I want to see my father.
我还要搞王后咧, 那一定很爽.
I want to fuck the Queen, for all the good it does me.
你想找你父亲, 小子?
You want your father, boy?
他躺在某家酒馆的地板上,
He's lying on the floor of some tavern,
别人正朝他撒尿呢.
getting pissed on by his friends.
我父亲是国王之手!
My father is Hand of the King!
我不是小子. 我是临冬城的艾莉亚史塔克
I'm not a boy. I'm Arya Stark of Winterfell
如果你们敢碰我一下, 我父亲
and if you lay a hand on me, my father
会把你们俩的头砍下来插在枪尖上.
will have both your heads on spikes.
现在你是让我过去, 还是要我赏你
Now are you going to let me by or do I need to smack you
两个耳刮子才听得懂?
on the ear to help with your hearing?
你知不知道我派出一半的卫士去找你?
You know I had half my guard out searching for you?
你要向我保证以后不再乱跑了.
You promised me this would stop.
他们说他们要杀你.
They said they were going to kill you.
- 谁说的? - 我没看清楚,
- Who did? - I didn't see them,
- 但有一个是胖子. - 哦, 艾莉亚.
- but I think one was fat. - Oh, Arya. ( Sighs )
我没说谎! 他们说你找到了私生子
I'm not lying! They said you found the bastard
还有狼和狮将打成一团--
and the wolves are fighting the lions and the savage--
好象还有什么野蛮人.
something about the savage.
- 你在哪儿听到的? - 在地下城,
- Where did you hear this? - In the dungeons,
在龙的头骨附近.
near the dragon skulls.
你去地下城干什么?
What were you doing in the dungeons?
抓一只猫.
Chasing a cat.
( Knocks, door opens )
抱歉, 大人.
Pardon, My Lord.
有个守夜人想要见你.
There's a night's watchman here begging a word.
他说有要紧事.
He says it's urgent.
- 你叫什么, 朋友? - 尤伦, 打扰您了.
- Your name, friend? - Yoren, if it please.
这一定是您的公子. 长得跟您真像.
This must be your son. He has the look.
我是女孩!
I'm a girl!
是班扬派你来的么?
Did Benjen send you?
不是的, 大人.
No one sent me, My Lord.
我是来寻找守长城的人手,
I'm here to find men for the Wall,
看看这边地牢里有没等待发落的人渣
see if there's any scum in the dungeons
或许能在长城派上用场.
that might be fit for service.
哦, 我们会帮你征召新兵.
Oh, we'll find recruits for you.
谢谢您, 大人.
Thank you, My Lord.
但我来找您不是为了这个.
But that's not why I disturb you now.
您的兄弟班扬是黑衣军的一员--
Your brother Benjen, his blood runs black--
我和您一样是他的兄弟.
makes him as much my brother as yours.
我正是为了他才飞速赶来
It's for his sake I rode here so hard
差点把我的马都给累死了.
I damn near killed my horse.
还有其他人也在飞速赶路.
There are others riding too.
明天全城都会知道了.
The whole city will know by tomorrow.
知道什么?
Know what?
这事最好私下谈, 大人.
Best said in private, My Lord.
走吧. 我们等会再谈.
Go on. We'll talk more later.
乔里, 带她回房间.
Jory, take her safely to her room.
走吧, 小姐. 您听见您父亲的吩咐了.
Come along, My Lady. You heard your father.
我父亲有多少守卫?
How many guards does my father have?
在君临这儿吗? 有五十个.
Here in King's Landing? 50.
你不会让任何人有机会杀他, 对不对?
You wouldn't let anyone kill him, would you?
您不必担心这个, 小姐.
No fear on that count, little lady.
- 怎么? - 是关于您夫人的, 大人.
- Well? - It's about your wife, My Lord.
她抓了小恶魔.
She's taken the Imp.
( Neighs )
欢迎您远道而来, 史塔克夫人.
You're far from home, Lady Stark.
请问您是谁?
To whom do I speak?
瓦狄斯伊根, 艾林谷的骑士.
Ser Vardis Egan, knight of the Vale.
艾林夫人知道您来访吗?
Is Lady Arryn expecting your visit?
我们事先来不及通知.
There was no time to send word.
冒昧问一句, 夫人,
May I ask, My Lady,
他怎么会和您在一起?
why he is with you?
正是为了他的事.
That's why there was no time.
- 他是我的俘虏. - 他看起来不象个俘虏.
- He is my prisoner. - He doesn't look like a prisoner.
我妹妹会决定怎么对待他.
My sister will decide what he looks like.
是, 夫人.
Yes, My Lady.
她在家里.
She will at that.
鹰巢城. 据说它是无法攻破的.
The Eyrie. They say it's impregnable.
给我十个勇士和几柄长枪--
Give me 10 good men and some climbing spikes--
我保证搞定那个婊子.
I'll impregnate the bitch.
我喜欢你.
Tyrion: I like you.
史塔克大人, 请您前往
Lord Stark, your presence has been requested
御前会议厅出席紧急会议.
in the small council chamber. A meeting has been called.
我需要先单独面见国王.
I need to see the King first-- alone.
国王已经在会议厅了, 大人.
The King is at the small council meeting, My Lord.
他正召你前去.
He has summoned you.
- 是关于我妻子的事吗? - 不是, 大人.
- Is it about my wife? - No, My Lord.
我想是有关丹妮莉丝坦格利安的事.
I believe it concerns Daenerys Targaryen.
那贱货怀孕了.
The whore is pregnant.
- 你在谈论谋杀一个婴儿. - 我警告过你
- You're speaking of murdering a child. - I warned you
会发生这种事. 还在北境时我就警告过你,
this would happen. Back in the North, I warned you,
但你却充耳不闻.
but you didn't care to hear.
好吧, 现在你听清楚.
Well, hear it now.
我要他们死, 母子两个一起死.
I want 'em dead, mother and child both.
外加那个笨蛋韦赛里斯.
And that fool Viserys as well.
这样说够明白了吧?
Is that plain enough for you?
我要他们一起死.
I want them both dead.
你这样做会永远失去荣誉.
You will dishonor yourself forever if you do this.
荣誉?!
Honor?!
我需要统治七大王国!
I've got Seven Kingdoms to rule!
一个国王, 七个王国.
One King, Seven Kingdoms.
你以为靠荣誉能统治七国吗?
Do you think honor keeps them in line?
你以为靠荣誉能保持和平吗?
Do you think it's honor that's keeping the peace?
是恐惧-- 恐惧和鲜血.
It's fear-- fear and blood.
那我们和疯王还有什么区别.
Then we're no better than the Mad King.
小心, 奈德. 你小心点.
Careful, Ned. Careful now.
你要刺杀一个女孩子
You want to assassinate a girl
仅仅因为八爪蜘蛛听到一个谣言?
because the Spider heard a rumor?
不是谣言, 大人. 前朝公主确实怀孕了.
No rumor, My Lord. The princess is with child.
消息的来源呢?
Based on whose information?
乔拉莫尔蒙爵士.
Ser Jorah Mormont.
他现在为坦格利安家族效力.
He is serving as advisor to the Targaryens.
莫尔蒙? 你这消息来源于
Mormont? You bring us the whispers
千里之外的一个叛徒, 能可靠吗?
of a traitor half a world away and call it fact?
乔拉莫尔蒙是个奴隶贩子, 但不是叛徒.
Jorah Mormont's a slaver, not a traitor.
我知道对重视荣誉的人来说区别不大.
Small difference, I know, to an honorable man.
他违犯了律法, 背叛了家族, 逃离了祖国.
He broke the law, betrayed his family, fled our land.
我们要听信这种人的消息去行刺?
We commit murder on the word of this man?
如果他是对的呢?
Robert: And if he's right?
如果她生下一个儿子呢?
If she has a son?
一个坦格利安率领一支多斯拉克大军...
A Targaryen at the head of a Dothraki army...
- 那怎么办? - 狭海依旧隔在中间.
- What then? - The Narrow Sea still lies between us.
我才不担心多斯拉克人
I'll fear the Dothraki
除非他们能教会他们的马在水上走路.
the day they teach their horses to run on water.
什么也别做?
Do nothing?
这就是你睿智的建议?
That's your wise advice?
等我们的敌人登陆了再说?
Do nothing till our enemies are on our shores?
你们都是我的重臣!
You're my council. Counsel!
来跟这满脑子荣誉的傻瓜讲讲道理.
Speak sense to this honorable fool.
我了解您的顾虑, 大人.
I understand your misgivings, My Lord.
我实话实说. 我们讨论的是件可怕的事
Truly, I do. It is a terrible thing
是件卑鄙的事.
we must consider, a vile thing.
然而我们这些冒昧为政的人有时必须
Yet we who presume to rule must sometimes
为了国家的福祉做一些卑鄙的事.
do vile things for the good of the realm.
倘若诸神真给了丹妮莉丝一个儿子,
Should the gods grant Daenerys a son,
整个国家将血流成河.
the realm will bleed.
我对这个女孩毫无恶感,
I bear this girl no ill will,
但是倘若多斯拉克人真的入侵,
but should the Dothraki invade,
会有多少无辜百姓死于非命?
how many innocents will die?
会有多少繁华城镇付之一炬?
How many towns will burn?
那么比较明智甚或比较仁慈的做法,
Is it not wiser, kinder even,
会不会是让她现在死去
that she should die now
以使万千生灵能平安地活下去呢?
so that tens of thousands might live?
我们多年以前就该杀掉他们俩了.
We should have had them both killed years ago.
当你发现跟自己上床的原来是个丑女,
When you find yourself in bed with an ugly woman,
最好的做法就是闭上眼睛赶紧办事.
best close your eyes, get it over with.
杀了她. 越快越好.
Cut her throat. Be done with it.
我跟随你冲锋陷阵--
I followed you into war--
进行过两场战争,
twice,
从不怀疑,
without doubts,
从无顾虑.
without second thoughts.
但这次我不能跟随你.
But I will not follow you now.
和我一起长大的劳勃
The Robert I grew up with
绝不会在一个尚未出生的孩子的阴影下颤抖.
didn't tremble at the shadow of an unborn child.
那么刺杀她的计划.
She dies.
我绝对不会参与.
I will have no part in it.
你是国王之手, 史塔克大人.
You're the King's Hand, Lord Stark.
你必须听我命令, 否则我就另请高明.
You'll do as I command or I'll find me a hand who will.
那我祝他胜任愉快.
And good luck to him.
我本以为你会比疯王强.
I thought you were a better man.
滚. 滚, 去你的吧.
Out. Out, damn you.
我受够你了.
I'm done with you.
快滚回临冬城去!
Go, run back to Winterfell!
否则我会把你的头砍下来插在抢尖上!
I'll have your head on a spike!
我自己来, 你这傻瓜!
Robert: I'll put it there myself, you fool!
你认为你太善良了? 太骄傲太荣誉了?
You think you're too good for this? Too proud and honorable?
这是一场战争!
This is a war!
我要带我女儿们一起走.
I'll go ahead with my daughters.
让她们准备好. 你去安排.
Get them ready. Do it yourself.
- 别向任何人透露. - 好的, 大人.
- Don't ask anyone for help. - Right away, My Lord.
贝里席大人想见您.
Lord Baelish is here for you.
陛下他后来还接着骂了一通
His Grace went on about you at some length
在你离开之后.
after you took your leave.
其中还出现了 "背叛" 这样的字眼.
The word "treason" was mentioned.
你有什么事?
What can I do for you?
您打算何时回临冬城?
When do you return to Winterfell?
怎么? 这与你何干?
Why? What do you care?
如果您明天傍晚还在这儿,
If you're still here come nightfall,
我想带您去见见琼恩艾林...
I'll take you to see the last person Jon Arryn
病倒前找过的最后一个人.
spoke with before falling ill.
如果您对此仍有兴趣得话.
If that sort of thing still interests you.
我没时间.
I don't have the time.
花不了一个小时的. 你决定吧.
It won't take more than an hour. But as you please.
把我们的所有人都找齐
Round up all the men we have
布置在女孩房间外面.
and station them outside the girls' chambers.
- 你手下最好的两个剑士是谁? - 海华和韦尔.
- Who are your best two swords? - Heward and Wyl.
让他们到马房找我.
Find them and meet me at the stables.
你未经许可把他带到这里来?
You bring him here without permission?
让他弄脏我的家?
You pollute my home with his presence?
( Suckling )
你的姨妈做了一件坏事, 罗宾,
Your aunt has done a bad thing, Robin,
一件非常坏的事.
a very bad thing.
你还记得她, 是吧?
You remember her, don't you?
他漂亮吧?
Isn't he beautiful?
也很强壮. 琼恩很清楚.
And strong too. Jon knew it.
他的临终遗言就是 "种姓强韧."
His last words were "the seed is strong."
他要大家都知道
He wanted everyone to know
他儿子长大后会是个强壮的男子汉.
what a good, strong boy his son would grow up to be.
看看他, 全艾林谷的领主.
Look at him, the Lord of all the Vale.
莱莎,
Lysa,
是你写信告诉我关于兰尼斯特家的事,
you wrote me about the Lannisters,
- 警告我-- - 我是叫你离他们远点!
- warning me-- - To stay away from them!
而不是带他们来这里!
Not to bring one here!
妈咪?
Mommy?
- 他就是那个坏人吗? - 是的.
- Is that the bad man? - It is.
( Creepy laugh )
他好小呀.
He's little.
他是兰尼斯特家的小恶魔提利昂.
Lysa: He's Tyrion the imp of house Lannister.
害死你父亲的就是他.
He killed your father.
就是他谋杀了国王之手!
He murdered the Hand of the King!
哦, 他也是我杀的?
Oh, did I kill him too?
我还真是个忙碌的家伙.
I've been a very busy man.
你最好管紧你的舌头!
You will watch your tongue!
这些都是艾林谷的骑士.
These men are knights of the Vale.
个个都对琼恩艾林敬爱有加.
Every one of them loved Jon Arryn.
个个都愿意为我牺牲性命.
Every one of them would die for me.
要是我有什么不测,
If any harm comes to me,
我老哥詹姆很乐意料理他们.
my brother Jaime will see that they do.
你不能伤害我们.
You can't hurt us.
没人能在这里伤害我们. 告诉他, 妈咪!
No one can hurt us here. Tell him, mommy!
- 告诉他! - 嘘, 我亲爱的孩子.
- Tell him! - Shh shh shh, my sweet boy.
他只是想吓唬我们.
He's just trying to frighten us.
兰尼斯特家的人全都是骗子.
Lannisters are all liars.
谁也别想伤害我的宝贝.
No one will hurt my baby.
妈咪...
Mommy...
我想看那个坏人飞.
I want to see the bad man fly.
也许会的, 我的小宝贝.
Perhaps you will, my little love.
这个人是我的俘虏.
This man is my prisoner.
我不能任他受到伤害.
I will not have him harmed.
瓦狄斯爵士,
Ser Vardis,
我姐姐的小客人累了.
my sister's guest is weary.
带他下去休息.
Take him down below so he can rest.
把他介绍给莫德.
Introduce him to Mord.
你去睡觉吧, 侏儒.
You go sleep, dwarf man.
好好睡觉, 小侏儒!
( Laughing ) Sleep good, little dwarf man!
( Slams, lock clanks )
( Wind gusting )
史塔克能保住脑袋算是万幸.
Lord Stark's lucky he still has a head.
劳勃会发上几天的火, 但他不会做什么.
Robert will rant for a few days, but he won't do anything.
他喜欢这个人.
He adores the man.
你嫉妒了.
( Surprised ) You're jealous.
你确信这不会受伤吗?
Are you sure this won't hurt?
除非我手滑.
- Only if I slip. - ( Scraping )
- 你喜欢我这个样子? - 嗯.
- And you'd prefer me like this? - Mm-hmm.
如果你想要没毛的, 也许应该找个小男孩.
If you want hairless, maybe you should find a little boy.
我想要的是你.
I want you.
我兄弟觉得任何没上过战场的人都不算男人.
My brother thinks that anyone who hasn't been to war isn't a man.
他对待我好象我是个被宠坏的孩子.
He treats me as if I'm a spoiled child.
哦, 你不是吗?
Oh, and you're not?
洛拉斯提利尔, 百花骑士?
Loras Tyrell, the knight of the flowers?
你参加过几场战争?
How many wars have you fought in?
哦, 你父亲为你这套盔甲花了多少钱?
Oh, and how much did your father spend on that armor of yours?
别动.
Hold still.
劳勃和史坦尼斯总是说我不够强悍,
All I ever hear from Robert and Stannis is how I'm not tough enough,
说我害怕看见血--
how I squirm at the sight of blood--
但看到那人在肉搏战被打下眼球确实很恶心.
you did vomit when that boy's eye was knocked out in the melee.
他的眼球还在眼眶外乱晃!
His eye was dangling out of the damn socket!
他学艺不精就不该上场肉搏.
He shouldn't have entered the melee if he didn't know how to fight.
你说得轻松.
Easy for you to say.
不是所有人都拥有剑术天赋.
Not everyone is such a gifted swordsman.
这不是天赋. 不是什么人给我的.
( Groans ) It's not a gift. No one gave it to me.
我剑术好是因为我勤于练习--
I'm good because I work at it--
自我能拿棒子的时候起每天都练习.
every day of my life since I could hold a stick.
我也可以整天练习, 每天练习,
I could work at fighting all day, every day,
但还是不可能比得上你.
and still never be as good as you.
好吧, 我想这一不定.
Yes well, I guess we'll never know.
( Sighs )
- 所有地方? - 所有地方.
- Everywhere? - Everywhere.
最后会怎样?
So how did it end up?
那个坦格利安女孩会死吗?
The Targaryen girl will die?
必须这样做, 虽然不令人愉快.
It needs to be done, unpleasant as it is.
劳勃很关心这个.
Robert's rather tasteless about it.
每次他说要杀死她,
Every time he talks about killing her,
桌子都被敲得跳起来.
I swear the table rises six inches.
可惜他对他妻子没这么大热情.
It's a shame he can't muster the same enthusiasm for his wife.
他确实对她家的钱有深深的欲望.
He does have a deep, abiding  lust for her money.
你无法小看兰尼斯特家--
You have to give it to the Lannisters--
他们也许是最傲慢最无聊的混蛋
they may be the most pompous, ponderous cunts
令诸神都难以忍受,
the gods ever suffered to walk the world,
但他们的钱多得不象话.
but they do have outrageous amounts of money.
我的钱倒也不少.
I have an outrageous amount of money.
没有兰尼斯特家那样多.
Not as much as the Lannisters.
但还是比你多得多.
( Laughing ) But a lot more than you.
劳勃要带我一起去打猎.
Robert's threatening to take me hunting with him.
上次我们去了两星期.
Last time we were out there for two weeks.
下雨时还在树林里打滚, 连续好几天,
Tramping through the trees in the rain, day after day,
为了能把矛刺进什么东西的肚子里.
all so he can stick his spear into something's flesh.
哦. 劳勃喜欢杀戮.
Oh. But Robert loves his killing.
- 他是国王. - 嗯.
- And he's the King. - Hmm.
- 为什么他能称王? - 因为他喜欢杀戮.
- How did that ever happen? - Because he loves his killing.
他也曾经擅长杀戮.
And he used to be good at it.
你知道谁应该称王吗?
Do you know who should be king?
- 别开玩笑. - 我是认真的.
- Be serious. - I am.
我父亲会做你的后盾.
My father could be your bank.
我从未上过战场, 但我会为你而战.
I've never fought in a war before, but I'd fight for you.
我在继承顺位中排第四.
I'm fourth in line.
劳勃在疯王的继承顺位中排第几呢?
And where was Robert in the line of royal succession?
乔佛里是个混蛋.
Joffrey is a monster.
- 托曼才八岁. - 史坦尼斯呢?
- Tommen is eight. - Stannis?
史坦尼斯象只龙虾那样强硬古板.
Stannis has the personality of a lobster.
但他仍是我的哥哥.
He's still my older brother.
- 你干什么?! - 看一看.
- ( Gasps ) What are you doing?! - Look at it.
你割伤我了.
You cut me.
不过是血. 我们体内都有血.
It's just blood. We've all got it in us.
有时会流出一点.
Sometimes a little spills.
如果你成为国王, 你会经常看见血.
If you become King, you're going to see a lot of this.
你必须习惯.
You need to get used to it.
继续. 看.
Go on. Look.
人们爱戴你.
People love you.
他们愿意服侍你, 因为你待他们仁慈.
They love to serve you because you're kind to them.
他们希望靠近你.
They want to be near you.
你愿意做必须做的事情,
You're willing to do what needs to be done,
你也从不幸灾乐祸.
but you don't gloat over it.
你不喜欢杀戮.
You don't love killing.
是哪本书上写着: 权力...
Where is it written that power
是万恶之源?
is the sole province of the worst?
王座只属于...
That thrones are only made
仇恨和恐惧?
for the hated and the feared?
你将会是一个受人爱戴的好国王.
You would be a wonderful King.
我很遗憾你和奈德史塔克的联姻没成.
I'm sorry your marriage to Ned Stark didn't work out.
你们本会是和睦的亲家.
You seemed so good together.
我很高兴能做件让你开心的事.
I'm glad I could do something to make you happy.
没有首相, 一切将变得混乱不堪.
Without a Hand, everything will fall to pieces.
我想你的目的是
I suppose this is where you tell me
要我把这位子给你的兄弟詹姆.
to give the job to your brother Jaime.
不.
No.
他不够严肃.
He's not serious enough.
我要为奈德史塔克说句话:
I'll say this for Ned Stark:
他足够严肃.
He's serious enough.
就这样失去他值得吗?
Was it really worth it? Losing him this way?
我不知道.
I don't know.
但是我知道这一点:
But I do know this:
如果坦格利安家的女孩说服她的马王丈夫发动入侵
If the Targaryen girl convinces her horselord husband to invade
如果多斯拉克大军渡过狭海...
and the Dothraki horde crosses the Narrow Sea...
我们将无法阻止他们.
We won't be able to stop them.
多斯拉克人从不乘船, 小孩子都知道.
The Dothraki don't sail. Every child knows that.
他们缺乏纪律. 他们没有盔甲.
They don't have discipline. They don't have armor.
他们没有攻城武器.
They don't have siege weapons.
你的把戏耍得真不错:
It's a neat little trick you do:
你动的是你的嘴唇, 说的却是你父亲的话.
You move your lips and your father's voice comes out.
我父亲说错了吗?
( Huffs ) Is my father wrong?
让我们假设韦赛里斯坦格利安真的登陆了
Let's say Viserys Targaryen lands
带着四万多斯拉克哮吼武士.
with 40,000 Dothraki screamers at his back.
我们可以退入城堡--
We hole up in our castles--
这是明智的对策-- 只有傻瓜
a wise move-- only a fool
才会在开阔地带与多斯拉克人硬拼.
would meet the Dothraki in an open field.
他让我们呆在城堡里.
They leave us in our castles.
他们会洗劫并焚毁城镇,
They go from town to town, looting and burning,
杀死所有不能躲进城里的人,
killing every man who can't hide behind a stone wall,
抢走我们所有的粮食和牲畜,
stealing all our crops and livestock,
将我们的女人和孩子掠为奴隶.
enslaving all our women and children.
多久之后, 七国的百姓将不再支持
How long do the people of the Seven Kingdoms stand behind
他们临阵退缩的国王, 胆小如鼠的国王
their absentee King, their cowardly King
躲藏在高墙后的国王?
hiding behind high walls?
七国的百姓会在多久之后认定韦赛里斯坦格利安
When do the people decide that Viserys Targaryen
才是真正合法的君主?
is the rightful monarch after all?
但我们兵力还是比他们多.
We still outnumber them.
五和一哪个更大?
Which is the bigger number: Five or one?
五.
Five.
五...
Five...
一.
One.
一支军队-- 一支真正的军队
One army-- a real army
通过一个领袖, 一个目标团结起来.
united behind one leader with one purpose.
而我们的目标已随疯王一起死去了.
Our purpose died with the Mad King.
现在我们的军队数量
Now we've got as many armies
只由我们口袋里的钱决定.
as there are men with gold in their purse.
所有人都希望改变.
And everybody wants something different.
你父亲希望拥有世界.
Your father wants to own the world.
奈德史塔克希望跑回北境把他的头埋进雪里.
Ned Stark wants to run away and bury his head in the snow.
你希望什么?
What do you want?
我们已经有九年没真正打过仗了.
We haven't had a real fight in nine years.
背刺不能算是战斗.
Back-stabbing doesn't prepare you for a fight.
现在整个王国只有:
And that's all the realm is now:
背刺和阴谋
Back-stabbing and scheming
拍马屁, 捞金子.
and arse-licking and money-grubbing.
有时我不知道究竟是什么在维系着王国.
Sometimes I don't know what holds it together.
我们的婚姻.
Our marriage.
( Laughing )
啊, 所以我们坐在这里
Ah, so here we sit
坐了十七年,
17 years later,
维系着一切.
holding it all together.
你不觉得累吗?
Don't you get tired?
每天都累.
Every day.
依靠仇恨能维持多久?
How long can hate hold a thing together?
嗯, 十七年算是很久了.
Well, 17 years is quite a long time.
是的, 很久.
Yes, it is.
她长什么样?
What was she like?
你从没问过她, 一次都没有.
You've never asked about her, not once.
为什么不问?
Why not?
起初, 即使是在私下提起她的名字
At first, just saying her name even in private
我都感觉会使她重获生命.
felt like I was breathing life back into her.
我想如果我不再提起她,
I thought if I didn't talk about her,
她就会从你心里逐渐消失.
she'd just fade away for you.
当我明白这绝无可能的时候,
When I realized that wasn't going to happen,
我则是出于怨恨而不提起她的.
I refused to ask out of spite.
我不想给你带来满足感
I didn't want to give you the satisfaction
让你觉得我心里放不下.
of thinking I cared enough to ask.
最终我明白我的怨恨对你来说算不了什么.
And eventually it became clear that my spite didn't mean anything to you.
事实上你还很享受我的怨恨.
As far as I could tell, you actually enjoyed it.
那为什么现在又问?
So why now?
莱安娜史塔克的鬼魂还能怎样伤到你我呢
What harm could Lyanna Stark's ghost do to either of us
难道我们彼此伤害得还不够深么?
that we haven't done to each other a hundred times over?
你想知道可怕的事实么?
You want to know the horrible truth?
我已经记不得她长什么样了.
I can't even remember what she looked like.
我只知道她是我唯一想要的人...
I only know she was the one thing I ever wanted...
有人将她从我手里夺走了,
Someone took her away from me,
七大王国也无法弥补我的空虚.
and Seven Kingdoms couldn't fill the hole she left behind.
我曾经也对你有过感觉, 你知道么?
I felt something for you once, you know?
我知道.
I know.
甚至在我们失去我们的第一个孩子之后.
Even after we lost our first boy.
实际上那持续了很长时间.
For quite a while, actually.
我们之前有过可能吗?
Was it ever possible for us?
有过这样的时候吗, 即使很短暂?
Was there ever a time, ever a moment?
没有.
No.
这个答案让你感觉更好还是更坏?
Does that make you feel better or worse?
没有任何感觉.
It doesn't make me feel anything.
( Door opens, closes )
她长得很像他, 不是吗, 大人?
She looks like him, don't she, My Lord?
她有他的鼻子, 他的黑发.
She has his nose, his black hair.
对.
Aye.
您见到他的时候请告诉他, 大人.
Tell him when you see him, My Lord.
如果您高兴的话, 告诉他她有多漂亮.
If it please you, tell him how beautiful she is.
我会的.
I will.
告诉他我没跟过其他人.
And tell him I've been with no one else.
我以旧神与新神之名起誓, 大人.
I swear it, My Lord, by the old gods and new.
我不想要金银珠宝,
I don't want no jewels or nothing,
我只要他的人.
just him.
国王对我一直很好.
The King was always good to me.
琼恩艾林来看你的时候,
When Jon Arryn came to visit you,
他想要什么?
what did he want?
他不是那种人, 大人.
He wasn't that sort of man, My Lord.
他只想知道这孩子是不是开心,
He just wanted to know if the child was happy,
是不是健康.
healthy.
很健康.
He looks healthy enough to me.
这姑娘什么也不要.
The girl shall want for nothing.
妓院是比商船好得多的投资,
Brothels make a much better investment than ships,
我发现...
I've found.
妓女很少会沉.
Whores rarely sink.
你对劳勃国王的私生子女知道多少?
What do you know of King Robert's bastards?
嗯, 简单地说, 他生得比你多.
Well, he has more than you, for a start.
- 多多少? - 有关系吗?
- Ned: How many? - Does it matter?
只要上过的女人够多, 总有人会送你大礼.
If you fuck enough women, some of them will give you presents.
琼恩艾林把他们都找出来了. 为什么?
And Jon Arryn tracked them all down. Why?
他是国王之手. 也许劳勃要他代为照顾吧.
He was the King's Hand. Perhaps Robert wanted them looked after.
他这人充满父爱.
He was overcome with fatherly love.
走吧.
Come.
- 乔里! - 大人.
- Jory! - My Lord.
这么小小的一群狼.
Such a small pack of wolves.
退后, 爵士. 这是国王之手.
Stay back, Ser. This is the Hand of the King.
曾是国王之手.
Was the Hand of the King.
现在我不知道他是什么--
Now I'm not sure what he is--
好象是某个遥远地方的领主.
lord of somewhere very far away.
你这是什么意思, 兰尼斯特?
( Running ) What's the meaning of this, Lannister?
躲到安全的地方去.
Get back inside where it's safe.
我正在找我兄弟.
I'm looking for my brother.
你还记得我兄弟吧, 是不是, 史塔克大人?
You remember my brother, don't you, Lord Stark?
头发黄, 舌头利, 个子矮.
Blond hair, sharp tongue, short man.
我记得很清楚.
I remember him well.
似乎他在路上碰到了点麻烦.
It seems he had some trouble on the road.
您不知道他出了什么事吧, 是不是?
You wouldn't know what happened to him, would you?
他是我下令逮捕的
He was taken at my command
以为其罪行负责.
to answer for his crimes.
大人!
- Littlefinger: My lords! - ( Horse neighs )
我去找都城守卫队.
I'll bring the city watch.
来吧, 史塔克.
Come, Stark.
我宁愿你死的时候手里拿着剑.
I'd rather you die sword in hand.
- 如果你再敢威胁我家大人-- - 威胁?
- If you threaten My Lord again-- - Threaten?
事实上, "我打算把你家大人
As in, "I'm going to open your lord
劈成两半, 看史塔克家的人倒底是什么做的"?
from balls to brains and see what Starks are made of"?
你杀了我,
You kill me,
你的兄弟必死无疑.
your brother's a dead man.
你说得对.
You're right.
饶他一命. 把他手下都宰了.
Take him alive. Kill his men.
( Screams )
呀!
Yah!
我兄弟, 史塔克大人--
My brother, Lord Stark--
我想要他回来.
we want him back.
( Neighs )
( Theme music playing )
== 翻译: freesand ==
== sync, corrected by elderman ==